Daryl Roberson

Software Engineer - Shonborn-Becker Systems Inc

Belton, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Daryl-Roberson/55136cd4a193ae9c

Systems Engineer for the Software Engineering Center (SEC) TSI Automation Team, utilizing Expertise Engineering skills to Develop, Test, and Integrate Service Management Automation (SMA) and Desired State Configuration (DSC) into the TSI Enterprise Architecture to deploy autonomously Microsoft enterprise applications. Over 8 years of direct technical experience.

Possess active SECRET Clearance

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Shonborn-Becker Systems Inc - Aberdeen Proving Ground, MD - 2015 to Present

CERDEC CP&I

- Designed and implemented custom solutions to deploy Microsoft Enterprise application with minimal user interaction
- Worked closely with Microsoft Engineer/Consultants to integrate the new technologies within the TSI Applications.
- Knowledge of PowerShell 5.0, VMWare 5.5 and Power CLI 5.5.
- Developed PowerShell Automation scripts utilizing Desired State Configuration (DSC) and Service Management Automation (SMA) frameworks.
- Evaluated the interface between hardware and software, operational requirements, and characteristics of the overall system.
- Developed new solutions and supported existing software applications that offer large-scale and distributed implementations to a dynamic user base.
- Developed and applied advanced methods, theories, and research techniques in the investigation and solution of complex and advanced software applications and problems.

Lead Test Engineer

Shonborn-Becker Systems Inc - Aberdeen Proving Ground, MD - 2013 to 2015

- Software Engineering Center (SEC), PM MC
- Solved engineering issues implementing, maintaining, and troubleshooting Microsoft Active Directory (AD). Tasks include the management of user accounts, groups, computers, domains, and organizational units within active directory.
- Familiar with deployment and operation of Windows Server Update Services and System Center Configuration Manager in a tactical environment.
- Conducted Engineering based Development Testing (architectures, test plans, network diagrams) on Product Manager (PdM) Strategic Mission Command (SMC) requirements for CS14, Common Operating Environment (COE) v1, and COE v2 baselines.
- Participated in Project Manager (PM) Mission Command (MC) and Tactical Systems Integration Facility (TSIF) working groups to develop test strategies, devices, and system architectures.
- Coordinated with PdM Tactical Mission Command (TMC) and SMC representatives to determine test support requirements at the TSIF for the execution of Army and Joint certification test events as well as System of Systems Independent Verification and Validation (IV&V).

- Provided detailed recommendations via teleconferences and ad hoc working groups to PdM SMC addressing system interoperability deficiencies based on analysis of test results and worked directly with local Software Engineering Center (SEC) development staff to implement solutions in a timely and cost effective manner.
- Attended Technical Assessments and Configuration Audits, and assisted PM MC Configuration Management (CM) for BCCS and TSI hardware and software.
- Implemented and maintained complex Battle Command Common Services (BCCS) architectures leveraging virtualization technologies to support Army level exercise and interoperability test objectives.
- Integrated Information Assurance standards against current and emerging baselines, and troubleshot issues.

Systems Analyst

JB Management - Fort Hood, TX - 2011 to 2013

Aberdeen Proving Ground, MD - PdM SMC

- Routinely reviewed architectures, installed, and configured systems in preparation for Army Interoperability Certification (AIC) test events and conducted testing to assess the systems compliance with Army and Joint technical interoperability standards.
- Coordinated with PM MC CM to implement standard processes for integrating, deploying, and configuring PM MC baseline products.
- Applied Information Assurance Vulnerability Alerts (IAVA) and STIG's to PM MC baseline products and troubleshot issues.
- Provided over-the-shoulder training of TMC and SMC products (BCCS, DDS, SAM, NRTS, Exchange, SharePoint, and CPOF) to CTSF Test Officers, Systems Engineers, and other designated personnel.
- Provided virtualization expertise and direct technical support to multiple Battlefield Functional Areas (BFA).
- Conducted Microsoft SQL Server 2005/2008 database management and administration on a daily basis to support the storage requirements for the BCCS Data Dissemination Service (DDS), Microsoft SharePoint, and Command Web.

Intern/Student

Tarleton State University - Killeen, TX - 2005 to 2011

- Provided engineering support and systems administration to the University's Computer Lab.
- Participated in engineering working groups, developing the network architecture and supporting test strategies for the expansion of the campus' Wide Area Network (WAN).
- Conducted testing of proposed software changes leveraging Sun Virtual Box and Sandbox software that enabled a testing environment isolating untested code changes and experimentation from the production environment.

SPC/E4

U.S Army Active Duty - Fort Hood, TX - June 2001 to June 2005

- 1/5 CAV
- Trained and Operated Force XXI Battle Command Brigade and Below (FBCB2).
- Maintained highly advanced equipment and personnel records.
- Maintained Secret Security Clearance

EDUCATION

M.S. in Information System

Tarleton State University 2011

B.S. in Software Engineering

Tarleton State University Central Texas 2010

SKILLS

Active Directory (2 years), Exchange (2 years), Microsoft SharePoint (2 years), SharePoint (2 years), VMWare (2 years)

MILITARY SERVICE

Service Country: US Branch: ARMY Rank: SPC/E4

June 2001 to June 2005

Trained and Operated Force XXI Battle Command Brigade and Below (FBCB2). Maintained highly advanced equipment and personnel records. Maintained Secret Security Clearance

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages • PowerShell, SQL, C#, XML Software

- VMWare 5.5, 6.5
- PowerCLI 5.5. 6.5
- C#.net
- Visual Studios 2015, 2017
- Windows Server [...] Active Directory, MS SharePoint, MS Exchange, MS Office, MS SQL